And welcome to North Greenwich Arena.
And this place is starting to really fill up.
The United States taking on Australia.
This is the final quarter final for the men.
The right to announce to the semi-finals.
We've seen some good ones already.
Mark Dorn, you want to recap the action
on the first three games for us?
I do.
The first quarter final, Russia and Lithuania.
There was Russia 83-74 getting the job done by nine points
and moving through to the semis.
And they will now play Spain, who in an ultra-defensive game
was able to win that one by 76-59.
France in, well, the territory that would have suggested
they would go on to win the game for the bulk of it.
But then they just got started.
Couldn't score them.
So Mugley fouls at the end of that one.
And Argentinant have just won their way through to the semis
against the winner of this game, 82-77 beating Brazil by five.
So it'll be Russia versus Spain.
And the winner of this game will pick on Argentina.
The introductions of Team Australia, the boomer.
Peter Crawford, Patty Mills.
Mills has been on a runner lately.
Unbelievable scoring outputs.
39 points in his last game.
Adam Gibson, Joe Engle, David Newley, Matt Delabadova,
the youngster, is 21 years of age.
David Borlo, Mark Orlington.
Aaron Beane, David Anderson, Matt Nielsen, the veteran.
Alex Merrick, that makes up the Australian team.
They are cooped by Brett Brown.
So I was lucky enough to call the last game,
Australia versus Russia in the preliminary.
And it was Patty Mills to the buzzer beat of the three,
with just 4.1 seconds.
The sideline ball went to Patty.
He's doing things that he hasn't done since four years ago
in Beijing when he really turned it on.
And they've come close to medals.
But they haven't had one yet.
And now the United States being introduced.
It came, not a lot of people say,
it's just a bunch of millionaires.
Are they a team, or are they just a list of right players?
Well, they're both.
Unlike other countries, the United States rarely
goes abroad to play in international tournaments.
Maybe the world championships will usually
take younger players.
So they can get the theater of the game, aren't they?
They are good at the theater.
Tyson Chen, the number four, Kevin Berant, number five.
LeBron King James, the best player in the world today,
number six.
Russell Westbrook, seven.
Ron Williams, eight.
Andre Idubwa, eight-bidala bag, Kobe Bryant, 10.
Kevin Love, the rebounder, 11.
James Harden with the beard, number 12.
Just called 13.
Great point guard.
The young star, Anthony Davis just drafted number one
in the NBA, 19 years old.
He wears number 14 in Camrillo, Anthony.
It's hard to say all that.
Who lit it up the other night's 30, 35 points in seven minutes.
The National Anthem of Australia.
And now the National Anthem of the United States, if you may.
The United States of America.
The American is giving the Australian a gift.
The Australian is giving the Americans nothing at this stage.
And then touching those gifts away.
It's an interesting part of the psyche of basketball, isn't it, when the Americans
are in town at all.
Just takes a different fear.
The U.S. coach by coach Kay Mike Shoshesky.
You spelled his name.
You would never be able to pronounce it.
It's a tie of y's.
And what they couple of eyes.
It's an amazing name.
He's an amazing man, obviously.
K-R-Z-Y-Z.
It starts with Shoshesky.
Winning his coach in University history in the United States.
Most of it with Duke.
I'm writing saying he's the only man to take America to two Olympic basketball competitions.
U.S. is one-thirteen-door medals and sixteen Olympic opportunities.
The record 122 victories and just five losses.
Australia has lost a couple here, early to Brazil and Spain.
And then the routed China and went on and a house of momentum coming in of it.
They do, but that's why they're crossing over the United States in the quarterfinals.
They're not later on because they lost those first couple of the United States.
On the other hand, well, you would say untroubled.
There's an average there.
Over 20 margins about 44 here.
I thought they were taken close by Lithuania, but there are what we've seen so far.
We told you about those victories to Argentina, to Spain and to Russia and the quarterfinals.
So there's one gap.
The United States to Australia goes one step forward and it's Argentina versus the winner of this one.
And Australia, missing one of their stars.
The injured NBA star Andrew Boggett would give them, give the boomers a whole different look if he was playing in the middle.
He's the star.
He's the star of Australian basketball.
Patty Mills out standing here, Joey Ingalls, with someone who might go on and will see Patty Mills, Joey Ingalls young Matt Delivert over.
He's been so impressive.
21 years of age.
I mean, college basketball in the US.
David Anderson and Matt Nielsen are the veterans.
They've played a lot of international basketball.
With Boggett in there, he'd be a genuine center at seven foot.
That would make it a completely different lineup.
Now the United States also many major players injured.
Wayne Wade, White Howard, Eric Rose and Chris Bosch.
All were named to this team.
None of them are here due to injury.
So a lot of players stepped up including Andre Igbojala, the young 19 year old Anthony Davis.
James Harden named the team late.
Three players from Oklahoma City, the team that finished runner up to the NBA championship.
LeBron James, finally won his title.
The fans here have a good time.
They're dressed in flags of all different kinds of nations.
Now we've seen the United States blow teams out.
We've also seen them almost lose.
Look at Wayne.
He had them on the ropes with two minutes to play.
As the officials, but then we saw them in their last preliminary game.
Game when Australia were hoping that Argentina could cause an upset.
So they wouldn't cross-hards in the quarterfinals down by just one point at quarter time.
And then the Americans got angry.
Yeah, the Argentinians decided to throw their waiter out.
Mistake and they were smashed in the second half.
So we've only seen them play their best for short periods.
And maybe we'll see it for an entire game right here right now.
Kevin Gurram.
Little bit up in that game.
I think you have what six three-porters in the row.
And each one further than the next.
Now despite the accents, it will be an absolutely unbiased commentary here.
But yes, you do have an Australian.
And you do have an American sitting alongside ready to cool this one.
Along with an absolutely packed house.
And everybody be you Australian American or otherwise will keep an eye on Patty Mills.
He's been a star of this tournament.
We played college ball at St. Mary's University.
Got cut by the Portland Trailblazers inside a contract with the San Antonio Spurs.
Had a good second half of the NBA season with it.
I want to stick it in London at the moment.
This one to see the Americans play ball.
Now that we are in finals mode.
Christ and Sandler getting the crowd involved very early.
Just off camera at the moment.
I don't know if you can hear that grumbly.
We are pounding in the background.
There's the youngster, Bella Badova.
Number nine.
Jowang goes number seven.
Perfect nickname.
Jingles.
We're about ready to get started.
Post–
3 8...
Waiting for the sport keeper to signal the start of the game.
and Jason Chammler got up a little bit too quickly they sat.
So Australia wins the first matchup the jump off.
Well there you go that might be the only time as Charlie is in front winning that the first
ball but if there to be any chance they must put some scoreboard heat on the American straight
away and if that means taking shots from the perimeter and Soviet.
But the United States has started off quite slowly against a few teams.
Trading to Asia.
Number 13 is Anderson a bomb from the way outside.
I saw a strip shoot and that was English.
The bronze James the headband.
Grant shark shooter.
Right where he left off from the previous game.
Daddy Mills the point guard swings it back out.
Nice pass down low position.
We're at an amber.
Little T.P. in his boots second if a good must sign the contest.
These Australians against the most powerful American.
This call as the point guard could be United States.
He's with 13.
Up pass.
Bam and home.
Nice and Charlie.
We saw him practicing that leap before the tip off and he went early in the tip off.
It was just all about that he's just been jumping out of his skit.
That's young Delabadova.
That comes off.
Australia had a mills for crew.
And we're tied.
He was also leaving.
Let me get it out.
We're he left off and that last game the buzzer made it to win.
He must light it up tonight.
Got a first foul of the contest and it'll be on Kobe Bryant pushing off.
Here's the run American as you look at that slam by Tyson Chandler.
Kobe Bryant of all people.
It hasn't got hot during the Olympic.
He's that because he is more of the individual.
That isn't fitting into the team than any of the others I wonder.
I think it's just because he hasn't got hot yet.
He's had some greater Olympics.
He's just not shooting well.
Meals with it.
Balls up again.
Howdy mills in Australia.
In the leads.
Here you go.
Two from two from Patty Mills.
They'll know that at the Americans.
Chris Paul working on Mills.
Durant again.
Answers.
It's a game in the number five.
The dough looking for mills.
Mills good feed down low to Anderson goes off his way out of bounds.
Eight to eight.
On an action in the opening couple minutes here.
We're at North Greenwich Arena.
It's a beautiful facility.
15 restaurants.
Beauty theater.
Nice cross over dribble and grain open.
Chris Paul.
Anderson.
Go angles.
He can shoot it from outside.
And Chandler comes away with it.
It comes far.
Toby Bryant.
Back out.
Good defense being played by the boomer.
Australia.
A very loose matchup zone.
Toby has a clock.
It's a crack.
His shot.
He's just having that kind of a limping.
Well, that's what he's talking about.
Maybe he doesn't have to go all the time himself.
Well, maybe he's taking shots.
He shouldn't be taking with the others.
He's sharing the ball.
That's a fear.
Brett Brown not happy with that.
Paul.
Good.
The US gets a new shot clock.
Durant's not going to need all that time.
Well, good over.
Man, that 21-year-old tries to bang in homes from outside.
Games loses it.
And opportunists go angles.
Angle scored 29 points at age 18 in his first NBL game in Australia.
And with authority, Tyson Chandler picks a crack down.
I saw that game and we knew we hoped that we would be a star.
And Chandler commits the foul.
You remember that game?
I was there.
You liked five.
And no less than Andrew Gaye, the best basketball Australia has ever had.
Who's also here watching Australia play call in the action back to Australia.
His suggestion that his performances in this tournament have been a standout to NBL Scouts
that he is ready to go.
Currently playing basketball in Barcelona.
I want to thank you for, we went to dinner with Andrew Gaye tonight.
Very nice man.
At least he didn't play.
He scored 789 points in five Olympic.
He didn't have to pay.
It's a Nielsen bank, one of two.
You're out.
Almost threw it away.
This is Chris Paul with it.
Eight seconds on the shot plan.
He'll be flying to the corner during the shoot.
We are.
And they've got an intentional foul call.
And Jason Chandler and Dave Anderson getting into it a little bit.
Anderson, thank you.
Get up to the Americans.
This is Shades of Hemaheel.
Shane Hale again.
Look into me.
Jason pushed them off.
Again, Australia has to be in the face of the Americans on the score sheet.
Definitely.
And David Anderson taking it a step further.
You got to let the attitude of Anderson.
Good to make these.
Close.
Anderson stands two meters 12 6-11 32 years old.
Did play with the Houston Rockets in 2009 and 10.
Because it was an intentional foul, Australia will also get the ball back.
And he's going to have to go down to the two thousand, including the downspour.
Three-team fouls at the moment.
But he's replaced by Carmelo Anthony.
And he had the hottest moment.
I will get in Olympic history.
Spored 35 points on less than seven minutes.
Yeah, that would be heavy.
Nice play to come up the bench.
And Anderson was looking to exact the crowd of men.
James.
Nice foul.
Let me tell you something about LeBron James that's unusual as you see him.
You see how big he is, how strong, how big he is, muscular.
He was that way in high school, really.
And nobody televised his high school games in the United States.
Not called each hospital.
Every high school senior game he had was televised.
That was the anticipation of him coming out early.
The decision, one of the highest-grading television programs in the history of US sports,
when he decided to tell us all that he was reaching up to the Miami Hague.
But it turned out to be more of a mockumentary.
Really angry with a lot of people about this isn't it?
So James is sitting around now.
This is his third Olympic.
He was on the team that lost the Olympics.
Did he play much?
He played.
Carmelo Amphan he was on that team too.
James with a rebound.
And he hooked up from the US and left him at least the last cup
with Carnival, the waste of all Australia, and they got down the flip.
Anthony.
Anthony from front of the arm.
And US with the steer.
That's Kobe Dunn.
And another reaching foul.
Another team in Chris Paul.
Nils.
Valar Nielsen.
Nilson next.
Team to deny the Americans the chance to go inside.
You're doing so the 15th.
And James.
Looks like it could have been an offensive foul, but it was a little late.
Mark Worthington getting position and James is so strong, so big and strong.
And he gets caught in and he's going to knock you down.
Aaron Baines.
A European player played at Washington State University comes in.
He's two meters eight six foot ten.
So he's in the little muscle inside.
He was shooting low percentage to start with.
I'm not going to be able to do that.
All right, and that's everything you're doing.
Low percentage to start with.
Nice play but can't finish Aaron Baines.
Back the other way.
You まあ have thisペ expectant didn't let the America's in that position.
Be careful when you attack be too fast and too high.
the
game's beautiful feed down.
The camp can be cranked in, scored a bucket.
Watch his pass.
And Australia snoozing a little bit.
We could watch it from up here.
Aaron Baines was right there.
He didn't say it coming.
And turned the wrong way.
The man on the Anthony's is third Olympics.
Can play every position on the court.
That's the one advantage that pro-chashky likes about having him.
They guard forward center at the eighth field.
Now place at the New York mix.
US up by seven, four minutes.
Still to play first quarter.
The man got after a good start and struggling rightly.
Angles is found by Anthony.
I'll take that foul.
The go to the line really needing these two.
The last couple of tricks down the floor.
As those turn the ball the way.
Or missed shots that they really should have made.
The captain Matt Nielsen to blame for a couple of those.
Nielsen, one of the rising stars in Stirling, Boston ball.
He's off top.
It's 24 years of age.
And goes make them both.
The run Williams now at point guard.
Grant and James are going the whole way.
And Grant started off making a shot.
But after that he's been ice cold.
Lob pass down low.
And not still by Aaron Bing.
Brown Williams saves it to the US.
James with a one-canced.
Not even called that a fade away because it was a sideways throw.
And once again with James's opportunity back comes the US.
And Westbrook throws the foul and Russell Westbrook in.
He also plays the Oklahoma City.
And also James Harden and Kevin Durant.
And he's certainly throwing these lighter in.
Very quick.
It's all worth it you can do with each and a foul.
You got a time out on the court.
Three minutes and change.
Left to go in the first quarter.
The United States by free over Australia 19 to 16.
Australia beginning and being able to keep pace with the US.
So beginning well and doesn't take much just a couple of trips forward.
It didn't quite work out.
It continued to work hard 19 to 16.
Trailing by just three.
United States playing the game.
You'd imagine they would.
The city 34% Australia 33.
Five and 15.
And it just those light ones they wasted.
They looked as if they were going to try and light it up on the outside.
Patty Mills making two quick ones since then.
Not so good.
What about the alley out pass?
A lot pass early on.
He was just jumping out of his skin Kevin Durant before the game started.
And he certainly doing getting that one in.
Followed it up.
Another couple.
The giant.
A month's giants.
The US was only made four of their last 13 shot attempt.
Out there.
Getting off to the red house.
Australia still hanging around down by three.
As big as stars as these guys are.
They were not able to get in the athletic stadium in time to watch the world's fastest man competition.
How do you know that?
Because I watched the video of them trying to get in.
And the guard did the job and said I'm sorry we're full.
They couldn't get in.
They were right at the gate.
I'll tell you now.
I was sitting just above the seat that I wasn't supposed to be in either and doing the great man.
St. Golden Action.
And yet all the Americans was being thought about.
Would you believe that that guy.
The lady with the glasses was an Australian.
And she stood firm and said no you haven't got a ticket.
I can't get in the boys.
We can see from here because we're big enough.
And I watched the semi-clinal and not sure where they watched the final.
But they were told no uncertain terms.
I don't care who you are.
Hopefully the Aussies are going to take that out of the shooting to this game here.
To the game.
Some pre-pro shooting issues.
Brad, newly we're getting out of here.
The third miss from the charity striped already for us.
Comes from Ron Jane.
Given go.
Games will spin move.
Good ball movement.
That's a low.
And has these sharp heart for the block.
Is she back?
No look past.
Orgis past the Russell Westfield.
Why an assist that time.
That he mills.
Go to the Ryan down hard goes Brad newly.
US 5004 newly appeals himself off the floor.
And we've got a whistle in the foul on Bane.
That he mills.
Mighty first couple.
These things.
One of the occasions.
And that's one of the reasons Australia funds himself.
He is with the six point deficit.
There's that gorgeous pass that assists the Chico.
That's exactly what it was.
It's been some really pretty stuff from the Americans.
I'm going to tell you something out there folks that you probably don't know.
Kevin love on the free throw line.
His uncle leads singer of the beach boys.
Mike.
I didn't know that.
The vibrations happening here for America.
They're a white 23 16 having the final fun.
Fun fun.
I certainly are.
I'm sure a lot of beach boy titles that you.
Working against a lot.
Just count book.
And he gets the rebound.
We'll give it.
Well, so the dribble after cross over dribble back can't for me.
Plenty of time in a stop.
That should be an offensive power.
It is.
Great defense that time.
I knew he stood up strong and.
Anthony knocks him down.
And now you hit a wrecking and you know stands.
Second foul.
Straight deep.
It needs to be more of that.
More importantly,
nice and importantly,
we'll go to the ball going forward.
Maybe try and get the ball into the life post themselves.
Still have to get something easy.
That's the attempt.
But no, it comes where with the steel.
And some by a Westbrook.
Little short because he is.
And the ball.
So one thing in the United States.
Where brings out to us that quickness and a lot of fouls.
Ratched up.
Quickly on Australia.
Teams can get forward.
Can't they try and get.
Keep pace with the Americans in the nice.
Have the ball and they're taking it up there and they move it too quick.
And conversely sometimes panic can easily occur in defense.
A hand goes a line.
And the kids foul.
A foul.
Really quickly.
Two unbanes, two unworthened, two undevoved overall already.
A couple of them is the both team.
It's going to be down for that $1.00 in.
Close.
That's marriage now in the line up.
There's a lot more strength inside.
Marriage with the put back doesn't go.
And another foul.
Referees can early regain to letting all the actions go.
Didn't call many fouls even when bodies were gone flying.
This one being called much tighter.
Mills with it.
That's a hard to get any kind of pace going.
So Williams now in the scoring column.
It's seven of ten U.S.
On this position.
Williams played.
Has now been traded and plays next year for a team that's a town
that's starving for a team.
Brooklyn just outside of New York City, one of the five girls in New York.
It'll be the Brooklyn Nets next year.
Reaching foul on Williams.
Games lost its pace and its pleasure with all these fouls being called.
You know when the referees attract more attention than the players.
That's a thing.
Tess something about Brooklyn.
They have very rapid fans and they had a baseball team for many years called the Brooklyn Dodgers.
And they left town to the west coast to California to become the Los Angeles Dodgers.
The famous baseball team in the United States.
A full city of Brooklyn.
Millions of people.
Still devastated.
So they're finally getting a sports team back.
And when you think of those accents, the strong accent you see in some of the movies.
That's from.
Betty Mills.
This is in bed.
The kids is going full back and eventually adds the two for Australia back with a night.
26 18 in the school.
And then the next day.
I found a low Westbrook.
This is.
Look.
I see people alive on the foul.
They started to shake their heads.
Andre Ego Dollar called for that foul.
Having a lot of trouble finishing the last two minutes of this first quarter.
So they have a good chance to win.
And then the first one.
One foul.
American now with.
H. So of course,
Marietta.
Four.
Need the two.
Marietta Serbian citizenship along with his Australian passport.
He played professionally in Spain, Serbia and Greece.
Two meters eleven.
One of the.
One will look at it.
The whole offensive series without a whistle.
No, we can't.
Westbrook went to the hoop.
He was fine.
It was in the hard three.
But took to get up.
It's time it.
It's into his eight immediately.
And that was a genuine foul out.
So Westbrook.
Both, uh, we did a basket.
David Balle didn't miss it.
So all these free throws.
And then the point starting to add up for the United States.
Australia's missed out on a lot of point opportunities.
What five of twelve in the free throw line?
That's right.
And for the U.S.
Nine of twelve of these men.
Seven Australians have fouls next to the only men.
And so Westbrook has five points next to his.
I can see.
Twenty seconds left to play in this first quarter.
Bath to ball.
A lot of finals have slowed us down here.
We had a lot of momentum early.
The U.S. jumped down in front.
Australia's been hanging on.
Eight seconds to go.
Mills takes it himself.
Thanks.
Move by patty.
One second to go.
The U.S.
Jack and the girl.
The shot will not count.
And as expected, the United States in front.
Twenty eight twenty one after the first ten men.
And there's the game stats.
He talked about the percentages from the stripe.
77% for America.
Four to two percent for Australia.
That goes a long way to putting you behind after the first
Fear to play from the field up.
Australia lit it up early.
And outside the three point lines by patty Mills.
They did go cold.
Again.
That's one of the reasons they're down.
13 rebounds to twelve.
Turnovers the same.
So it just mostly as it has been often that shooting position.
Here's LeBron James.
A massive audience here to see the Americans.
Many of them just love to watch LeBron in action.
He doesn't always do it himself.
He loves to assist.
He loves to kick it out.
Someone say even too much.
Kevin Durant.
He loves to go from outside.
And he can do some wonderful things.
And what about this?
Couple of sisterly from LeBron James.
Patty Mills doing what he does.
Basti's been so heart-leaky.
He's gotten ten points on the first quarter.
Yep.
That he's been at Stanley.
But he can't do it on his own.
He's not a big boy at all.
And Australia definitely glowsing.
Andrew Bogas.
We'll look at Durant once again.
All those poetry and notion to see him go to work.
And LeBron James, Dele Inglis and other Australians
who really needs to come into the game.
He can't realize that on that one.
But 28-21, Australia with a work to do.
A smallest player on the court.
Chris Paul.
Shot, mashed back in.
By Chandler.
Chandler got off for a good start.
But a couple fouls towards the middle of the game.
The US just keeps bringing more all-stars in.
That's one of the issues about playing against them.
Kevin Durant.
Kevin Lowe.
Westbrook.
Big Guadala.
And Durant Williams.
Durant.
Looks like he started the first quarter.
He's got three-three-fourers now.
Big Patty Mill is on Stanser.
Engels.
Triumphs with four-step pass.
Three-shifted away by Lowe.
Besides the famous uncle, Lowe has a famous father.
He's a family playing the NBA many years.
Not a love in that family.
Engels.
He's got closely deflected and a foul call on Lowe.
All you need is Lowe.
And I don't start playing with the beach boys.
I think the Beatles alone.
All Kevin Durant needs is a tiny little look at it.
And he will land another three.
He likes many Americans that he uses.
Australia is still giving away points from the charity strike.
And that is exactly what it is yet.
You have to shoot at 75 and above against the same of this quality.
If the game is over, the sky would turn the fouls.
He was on land and then he'd get them half into the game.
Lowe will get a breather.
Just underway in the second quarter.
North Greta, Serena.
USA in the light.
Australia in the green.
Grant, phase away.
Get the line by love.
Three-pointer out and way outside.
No good.
And now Lowe is down low on the deep foul call on Australia.
I think they got Anderson.
Yeah, scored on the fouls.
Continue to be right back up all the other.
But I have to be in there.
I have to find time.
I was giving the opposition space.
When you've got a team that's not as strong as you have.
As this team being body and certain amount of strong and shooting ability.
You have to really make the man everything.
The bronze chance now backhand for you.
Now since that government, if it looks familiar.
It's done it for years with the last one.
There's a lot of players going to be behind.
It may not be anybody left to play for Australia.
Hold it on.
They've shared it around.
That's the one thing in their favor.
No one really too much better.
I will roll.
Just a few and get two.
You lead for Williams.
Good defense.
Williams will take it for three.
And they call that foul after he was only laying on the ground.
That's a three point attempt.
So a free free throw foul on Anderson.
Anderson now another two.
There's as he came down, it was because of the way he fell.
Not because of the way Anderson had his arms up.
The contact was my wonder whether that foul would have been scored against him.
And then it had to come in.
10 points to margin all of a sudden.
Round away and forget to get a couple more.
That's your example, doesn't miss.
And the score is 12 to 15 now versus six of 14.
That's right.
Look at it.
The spirit generation is tattooed on the ring.
And the Olympics are all about.
It's time to get the youngsters to play sport.
Williams will five all of them from the free throw line.
Angle.
Anderson comes out.
Maybe Bryant still hasn't taken a shot from the outside.
It was wide and loved there.
It's not looked like the old Kobe Bryant at the Olympics.
Angle throws it across Anderson.
Anderson has been taken out of his hand.
Australia, Delabitova.
Three points basket by Brad Muirley.
He's had a few looks, Brad Muirley.
And he draws 20s first points for the back of the nine.
Williams again from the outside.
The media reply again near and close to difference.
Left alone Anderson.
Anthony fights for the rebound.
There's going to be a repaint foul thought on Australian.
And there may be a technical thought.
But extra aggressive there.
The captain of Australia, Matt Nielsen, when he went to the rep,
he was in his face.
He had the finger pointing and didn't like it.
Bowles on Newley his second.
Very frustrating for Australia.
23, 10, 10 in this period.
14 person fouls already in the half of the Australian.
James.
Not the screen from Anthony.
Goes into the corner.
There's Paul.
One of the quickest steps you'll see with basketball.
He'll be Brian again.
The other day, they take you up to Kevin Durant.
And a mock cheer from the crowd that there was a foul on the US player.
It's quite a few.
And him as well.
10.
Anderson will get a rep.
Ingalls to him bound for Australia.
39, 27 in the score.
The winner advances into the semifinals.
Nice defensive play by the ramp.
Grant and James against each other for the NBA championship.
Brian's second Olympics.
He's a 14 time NBA all-star.
He learned everything from his dad, Joe Jellybeam.
He played the NBA but also spent eight years playing professionally in Italy.
And Kobe was actually brought up in Italy.
He speaks for the time.
He's got a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little bit of a little
without a great mark, but I suggest something comes up I suggest something comes up I suggest something comes up
the
basket.
He will get the free throw.
David Doolee attacking the basket.
Nearly really athletic.
The games is taking the half
opportunities.
I say David moving up high.
Oops.
Doesn't matter.
He'll be happy just to be here.
He doesn't need you to get his name right.
I apologize. He misses Newly and
arrested a newly came.
He doesn't care about that.
He cares about this because
Australia won't give up.
He'll be dogged five minutes and
13 seconds.
You can see in the clock.
42-33.
Only 64-10.
That helps make it up to 47%.
Newly now with six.
Now the lead.
42-34.
US still in control.
Australia pressing in the back court.
William is back in.
We'll have two point boards in the lineup.
And it's a good shot.
More of a hope in a prayer.
A mills beats the US back on defense
and partially deflect it.
The nervous bull is good,
but he made all the contact with
Petty to tell him to go.
And the US defeats Ronda as well.
Ronda James decides to go to the basket.
He gets there most of the time.
Engels right back.
That's the sort of form that
Andrew guys has been talking about
that might take Joey Engels into the NBA.
And Mike Shoshesky wants a timeout.
He does not like the way the US has started to take a nap
a few times on defense.
So we got a timeout with the US on top of Australia.
Forty-fair-forty-six.
Shoshesky,
veteran coach has the respect of the players.
You would think that he would let the microphone in.
Brett Brown does.
You go, take out a switching.
We're going to bring you more of a line behind it.
So we're going to work to try.
If you don't have it,
get to the second side of a playside line.
We're counting the choke.
One, two, five.
His hands are red.
He's in.
And wrist north.
It was a good hit.
Wonderful to be able to hear the coaches Brett Brown.
The other coach of the Australian team.
Spent a lot of time in the NBA.
Knows the American way, but that doesn't matter much.
Your points, an interesting one with Coach Kay.
Is it he who won't let the microphone in or is it the players?
And Mike doesn't the IOC say,
you're in now competition, you lose it up.
I have my own theory.
The microphone picked up Coach Kay,
in Beijing, saying a few things that you never want to have
caught on with the microphone.
And that's my guess.
44-36, USA on top.
Halfway through the second quarter.
Australia giving them a game.
And then the mid-fifth.
Anthony McCormick.
One thing the Americans do,
if you start hitting those outside shots,
they will feed you the ball over and over and do the miss.
They'll do the lot pass down though.
Mills, two, three.
Oh!
The T-peat, that was deliberate.
Nice.
Now you're second to head.
I'm second to head because he almost knocked himself unconscious,
typically in.
Two points for David Anderson.
He's on the 7.
They'll take them any way they can, the Australians.
I'm not doing it.
Damn, spectacular shot.
Raise the ball like a little grip.
I'm not doing it.
It's amazing.
There he is.
He's got a 11 points.
Couple of sleepovers in the road.
There's Paul on Delova Dove.
Engle.
He's got a 14.
He's got a 15.
I can hear him yelling, oh my god up here.
He's used to NBA referees.
They kind of let the stars get away with a little more.
Anderson, turning around jumper.
And James comes away.
Love for three.
Big fella.
That's the line by James Anthony.
He was hot.
And again, love with the rebound.
And Anthony with the basketball.
Good work underneath by Kevin Love.
A couple of offensive rebounds.
Give the USA a second.
And a third chance at it.
Mills.
They've got numbers on the fast break.
William.
Fast down low.
A lot of contact.
William, pull up.
William's on fire.
13 points on Australia.
Once the tie down.
54-38 are scored.
214 left to go first.
I love the run.
William, see, does some one of the things.
Just another of those touch plays.
The Americans have got nice things in their roster.
Of course.
Let's see what the Australian coach has got in his.
David's going to shed it.
You're going to stay with him.
You're going to come back up.
And we're going to come right back up.
And we're going to come back up.
And we're going to come right back down.
We're going to get you the ball.
If you don't like it, you're going to play the unbeaten I'm with East.
The restrictions there go to David Anderson.
One of the veterans of the Australian team.
As he's basketballed, he and Italy.
He said, stay with it.
We're going to get you the ball.
And William's heating up.
He's staying with it.
Look at that.
There's the results.
Fans, I love it here.
I'm learning it all sports.
And it comes to basketball.
The American fans, perhaps a little bit more animated than most.
Crowd start doing the way, but yeah, but they don't sing.
Like the Australian fans and the others.
No chance.
I'm going to give this.
One day, one day that'll come to America.
Chanting and singing.
Two minutes left in the first half.
Three points away, Alphamar.
Grant came away with the rebound.
Just call with it.
Two seconds on the clock.
Grant's coming in.
Alpham is out.
He's not a big foul.
He does push off.
Yeah.
That's three fouls on Kevin Durant.
He'll have to sit.
Most teams, when they're outside,
sharpshooter gets three fouls to be in trouble.
But the US has backups.
Like Carmelo Anthony.
Yeah.
See if they can run that play.
Get the ball down.
No, the English and the Nielsen.
Engels takes a themselves.
And Gingles now with nine.
You go, Joe.
You have to make some more of those.
Yeah.
I think he makes some more of those.
Because it's getting away from Australia.
And Carm's Engels again.
He had somebody out in front.
Brad newly sat, and not to throw it to him.
Here comes the US that they can flag the ball down.
That's fast enough to do that.
He gets fouled by Matt Nielsen.
Oscar Ngui Premier.
F now has 3 fouls so still continuing to share the b half
around.
They are doing K 15 fouls for this first half in this and no
561.
net such as well as F.
one of the best passers in the end.
This is a boat that love another offensive rebound Williams from outside.
I'll strike you on the break.
Mills.
I know he felt the pressure of James.
That comes a lot.
James to love.
James another assist.
James wasted no time getting the ball along patty decided to go all the way.
Joe angles alongside to help out.
The other choice is you make.
Hey.
Mills draws the foul.
You're good.
Second on Ron Williams.
Wilson comes out with things and comes back into the game.
There's the beard.
Fear the beard.
James had an event tonight.
Is this his first appearance?
I'm not sure.
I don't know if you guys see the city bulls.
He spoke about everyone.
It almost looks like it's glued on.
Doesn't it?
And patty tack on the cap of the points from the line.
Lighting this first half.
US has done a great job of shutting him down this quarter after he scored 10 in the first quarter.
That's his first points here in quarter number 2.
ball and another ball and
the final seconds.
That'll do it.
56 42 the United States in front of
Australia after one half a basket
ball.
Get it a lot of offense in these
games and a lot of free throws
unfortunately as well both quarters
the identical score 20-21.
It's just noticing that's in the
7.9 it becomes full team and
that's a lot.
So as the players leave the
court quickly recapping this
scoring for Australia patty
Mills with a dozen angles nine.
David Anderson seven newly six
for the United States.
Strong Williams with 13 leads
away.
James seven less broke six.
Kevin Durant has those three
points and the United States
on the way to 100 points once
again in the basketball game.
So first one.
Then one.
We'll put the score a 1-20.
We only have one.
I'm going to go to the next one.
I'm going to go in the next one.
This is the right place for the people to be here.
This is the right place for the people to be in order to fit.
Too quickly, too much energy, too much energy, too few times.
How many years of work did you have in your career?
Yes.
How many years of work did you have in29.
How many years of work did you have in29?
Whoa!
I'm the one who loses.
I'll get to the right here, you really need to be there.
You need to be there.
I'm the one who loses.
I'll do my best to go to the next.
There you are.
Go on, go on, go on, go on.
Go on, go on, I got lost.
I have lost.
Maybe I'll be there.
You need to be there.
I have lost.
Do me anything.
Do me everything.
I gotta play.
You need to be there.
Hey.
Hey, who is running?
Do you think?
Hey.
Hello, everybody, and welcome back to the North Brennan-Cherina.
I'm Bruce Brezel along with Mark Doran, where the United States has run off to a 56-42 lead
at the half against Australia, shooting the difference to US 18 out of 42-43 percent.
Australia 15 of 38 shots, 39 percent.
Australia left a few points on the table, making only 9 of 17 free throw.
The US hitting 13 of 18.
A bunch of points Australia could have had at this point if they had made those free throw.
Yeah, and that man started the ball rolling, Cutty Mills.
He just disappeared from his screen, and he disappeared from the game a little bit, at least
from the score sheet after landing a couple of early threes to get Australia very much
up on the feet and the Australians.
Into this, it's interesting.
Everyone wants to come and see the Americans play.
It's one of the hottest tickets in town at every Olympic Games in London 2012.
No difference, but when they're there, they barracks almost to the other side because they
want America to be pushed.
They want to see the United States playing at their best, and they were playing certainly
up a gear than what they played for the majority that half early on because Australia
were there, and were in their face, literally David Anderson, getting aggressive, but it
hasn't quite paid off.
Every Olympic Games in 72 Australia has competed yet to win a medal for in 88 96 in 2007 in Beijing,
and it's going to be a similar result for the Australians, unless they do something amazing
in this second half.
As you look at the Americans warming up Coach K, Mike Shoshatsky has done a really good
job.
He's coached the last two U.S Olympic teams, winning a university coach in American history,
but he has been with international basketball for 14 years.
So on the sidelines, he's been an assistant coach.
He's taken the younger players.
It's not just showing up at the Olympic.
So the obvious question, why has he not coachable?
Does he not coach an NBA team?
Well, he's built almost a kingdom at Duke University known as it's a great academic
school.
It's a beautiful place to play basketball, and every young man wants to play for him.
So he doesn't need to.
That's a good answer.
That's a very good answer.
The other discussion point leading into the finals here is which was the better team, this
team now, or the original dream team that when the professionals were first allowed in
winning the gold medal, America, a winning margin of nearly 44 points.
Well, going into this game, the Americans had a winning margin and average winning margin
of 47.
And they lead this one by 14.
So they've got a little bit of work to do.
They're going to extend it out there.
Just a quick comment from you, which would you take?
Well, I think this team would beat him if they played today because the other team was
out of 50 years old.
But now, certainly, I think the first team that they've fielded, the players, Magic Johnson,
Larry Bird, they had 11 players that went into the NBA Hall of Fame out of the 12 on that
team.
Who is that?
The college kid.
That really that played really.
Yep.
And did he go on at all?
A couple years.
But that team, you know, you can't really compare them until these players all finish their
careers.
Here we go.
Second half beginning.
United States on top 56 to 42.
USA goes with that same starting lineup.
They went with the Mills trying to get Australia off the mark quickly and patty Mills with
15.
What do you have 39?
It's the last game.
A beautiful steal by Mills.
Well, we called him in.
And Chesky is so angry on the sidelines.
We said that's what it would be about.
Patty would have to leave the Australians back.
And he certainly has done that all of a sudden, adding five.
And we have named like 30 seconds.
Can they feed off that?
The green and go.
Brian throws it down low, tried to get an alley out pass.
And a lob pass a little bit too flat.
Here it comes Mills.
Engels for three.
Joe Engels now with a dozen.
And Australia has cut that lead quickly.
They're just six points.
So there's best two players there.
They're going to have to be the go-to guys.
The Brown James tries to answer.
Here it comes Engels.
And Mills got a little bit ahead of himself there.
Brian.
And offensive foul call down to a B. Brian.
And it comes up about that fact.
And that goes it goes up.
David front of him played good defense.
And if Brian hadn't lowered the shoulder,
he might have got away with something.
But once you do that, it's pretty obvious for the referee
to make that call.
And did the fate put the arms up and said,
oh, I am coming to get me.
Get me.
He did.
Can the Australians capitalize with more points?
Engels with it.
Looking to cut the lead before.
Or three if he makes this.
Incredible 11-0 run.
The Aussies inside a minute and 40 of this third period.
I said something remarkable would have to happen.
It has.
Australia.
Their ears are up.
Get my Durant from way outside.
And for the United States.
He's got four baskets.
All of them three points.
This is where the Australians count gets sucked in to moving both
two quick.
And what 24 seconds?
Use it up that you have to.
Nice feet from Delavid over.
Fighting inside.
The Americans come away with it.
And they step out of bounds.
From now.
The U.S. Mike Shoshesky wants a tie-money.
It doesn't like what he sees.
Our score at the United States 59 on Australia 53.
Clearly Toby Bryant's feet were out of bounds when he got that back.
He says what are you talking about?
You can see it 742 on the clock in Australia back in this.
What is the coach say?
I wish I had a microphone in that hole.
He is not pleased and he's letting them have it about how they're playing defensively.
Just sloppy.
And if the party tricks are going to start early, they may end up at Brett Brown.
What's he got to say?
It's great to be able to get in time and have a listen to the coaches.
He'll start some off.
He's losing meals and then watch defensively.
He picks this ball right off.
Let that well happen in for the two.
Then he gets angles into it.
Two young boys combining and there's the kangaroo.
The Boomer is a large male kangaroo.
That's the nickname.
This Australian team carries.
And I suppose that's where we could do a very Boomer there.
Australia will end ground down by six.
They're recorded.
And I am very surprised that Joe Angles would not get on the floor for that basketball.
It was not willing to die for when he had the opportunity.
I'm going to take desperation and acts of teams and ship us to close.
That's the rod too.
I'm here for a lot of pass here.
Brian in the corner.
There's the lot pass.
It's hold in the ring.
Right goal.
Thank you very much.
I saw them drawn it up on the sideline.
Televadova.
Young guy takes it for three.
Yes.
He plays college ball in the United States.
He's only 21 years old.
He plays at St. Mary's was the conference player of the year.
And a tiny little town called Meribar in country Victoria.
And a little Victoria.
And to Australia watching this of course.
Australia loves winning Olympic Games and love beating the Americans.
Not saying it's going to happen, but we're riding the hunt now.
Televadova's ball slapped away.
James.
Brian.
Brian's been trying to draw foul the last three times.
That I'm the awesome.
Here's the lot pass.
That was a set play that they ran out of that timeout.
It was flat, wasn't it?
But the, the, the, the, this isn't carried it off.
And then the three from Delivert over.
They're going to have to continue to shoot from outside.
Delivert over.
He's shown a small town.
He's got to like St. Mary's University because it is a tiny school.
And a small town in California.
That's the first points for Kobe Bryant.
And the all-time eating scores in basketball.
That's a field goal though.
As he's having a tough Olympic.
A lot of wholesale substitutions now for Australia.
Delivert, Nelson.
It's sit down and comes with him.
Nelson unit.
And run the cup.
Patty Mills back door.
And he's going to be a little bit more.
He's going to be a little bit more.
And run the cup.
Patty Mills back door.
And they got a little bit too far underneath.
James.
The ramp for three.
Can't find the rain.
And a little bit too cute last time up.
Australia is doing a very good job getting back on defense to prevent
getting from getting to the basketball.
And there's some.
Nice move.
David Abel.
And run the long-term David Anderson 30 times of age currently playing in Italy.
And for a lot of money playing basketball his head office to playing the NBA.
But there's nothing back loves playing for his country.
James.
And Kobe Bryant throws the foul on Newly.
And that's three now on Newly.
You'll play defense with your hands after the coach will say that's Carmelo Anthony coming
into the game for the United States.
Another score.
Patty from Chandler takes the seat so the U.S. going into the smaller lineup.
Anthony with eight points to far off the stadium and close to see what he's got in a couple of minutes
and then he's going to throw.
Angles does not like the call.
Take a look.
James drops the shoulder but Angles did not have set position on defense.
So King James dribbled on.
You got a very quiet eight points coming.
And then you have to say he though.
Imagine we back out to seven in a moment.
I thought it was related to you.
This is not happy.
64-58.
It's only a six point game.
Australia hanging tough.
Halfway through the third quarter and they caught away.
Just lost his plate.
Angles.
Just call.
Working on Mills.
This is about the time of the game where the U.S. has been able to blow it open except against Lithuania and they just never got it going.
Bobby Bryant.
Finally makes this job.
Barlow stolen away by Bryant.
Bobby Bryant.
Same spot on the floor.
Same result.
He has it.
Brett Brown walks the time out.
The United States has extended the lead.
It's 70-58.
4-37 left to go in the third quarter.
We've got a timeout.
He's come to the end.
I thought it might have been the go-to.
It wasn't necessarily that they went to Kobe.
He just did.
He's got the points.
He knew he was coming on the American one way or another.
That was the position in the game where I've seen it happen time and time again.
For some reason they seemed to coast for the first half of these games.
They were playing the Australian coach there.
It would be no surprise what's occurred.
He knows that's how the U.S. roll.
They can lead you in but they'll slam that door in your face just as quick.
And there's Bryant.
And he spent a whole career doing this.
As I said, if you're a fan at all, there's a still professional basketball.
Kobe Bryant has been on the radar for many, many years.
14 times in all the stuff.
A certain hall of favourites.
And a good ambassador of basketball.
And certainly to it.
This Australian team, a lesson.
It scored 81 points in a basketball game.
That's the second highest total in U.S. history behind a guy named Luke Chamberlain
who scored 100 in a game.
Bryant Uly just wants two.
He can't get it.
He's going to be a little bit out of the reach being a little bit cute with the ball.
The Australian's Bryant's high.
James left.
All on hands.
Hits and draws the fouls.
Watch James come away with this.
And nobody's in his way.
He's so strong.
He's got three or four from the line today.
Anthony and Mark Worthington were going at it.
They did well there to get front position.
And surely one the ball.
What can they do with it?
They can do that.
Brad Newley.
Three point basket.
And there's the Boona.
And it's late.
The bench.
On it's collective faith.
Chris Paul.
And he's going to be a little bit out of the way.
Oh, no.
I got one.
For Rampy outside.
Score.
No!
Anthony's being killed.
Permanent from jumping down low.
Worthington and Anthony have.
They've seen unpleasant trees in the last couple of minutes.
That's four fouls on Mark Worthington.
Yeah.
It hasn't been many minutes in the game.
I'm ready to come up with those.
Just in 12 minutes, though he's gonna take all the fouls.
And Anthony to the free throw night,
made his only attempt earlier and ate in the first half.
So he was certainly winning on that division
of the score shake, 21,000 to 15.
We're having to play hard, we're having to play tough.
This is the end of the whole game.
Third Olympics for Carmelo Anthony.
And he's in the hands, 203, 6 foot 8.
And the prime of his career.
The sweet sound, nothing but net.
Beautiful feed to Mills down, cutting underneath.
How he produces the same.
If he doesn't have the answers, it seems Australia doesn't have
to make these skies.
Williams now run out the point for the US Anthony.
Anthony on Mills turn around jumper doesn't go.
Joe angles with a beautiful feed the last time down.
Mills returns to the favor this time.
Carmelo.
I'm opening up, I'm in terror late.
Three minutes to play, third quarter.
And we'll transition now.
It's fairly a little bit of a difference.
Williams loses it.
And there's newly on the break end of the US force to fall
in an intentional foul called.
So it done moved by Russell Westbrook.
Australia will get the free throws and they'll get the ball back.
And there you see it.
So angles.
We'll go to the line.
Joe angles chance to cut into that ten point lead once again.
So just when you thought the United States was pulling away,
Australia fights their way back in it.
What a game by Joe angles.
It's the only 24 years old jumping jelly.
Yeah, now he's any very young man.
And championship in that NBA, which is played for the team,
who called the dragons and had two years in.
The second year they won it and then they were out.
They were gone.
Team had folded, he took off to Europe.
And he's now working towards some time in the US of A.
You would expect, perhaps in the not too distant future
the way he's been playing here.
So Australia on that intentional foul gets the ball back.
Patty Mills screwed three outside.
That would have given him so much more momentum.
Williams.
Australia back quickly on defense.
It died.
Great job.
It's stopping the US pass break.
It brought him.
And that passed all the way across.
Luckily found Carmelo Anthony.
He brings it.
Now Steve Scott's line it down.
You don't see him.
He's usually really high in the assists column.
But he has seven assists and 12 rebounds to go at his 10 point.
He's the loose make with the seal.
I think Kobe and LeBron are playing completely different games.
LeBron wants to share it first, and Kobe wants to shoot first.
Westbrook called for the foul.
his third personal. Australia
hanging close. Hang in top but it's
topsy up with it.
Engels in Barlow, it's changing.
Seven seconds on the shot class.
Five seconds. Engels gonna have to
take it himself.
Lock winding down.
And just got the shot off.
Can say it's been a while since he's
taken a shot.
And Barlow with the foul.
Who is officially the captain of the
USF?
That's a good question. They officially
had one. I've seen it listed for
just about every team but I did
not see it listed for the US.
Did you? No, that's where you're
out. Yeah, and I did not ask a
question. You wouldn't have the
answer. I just I wanted to hear
you out of this. Look at every
team shape that we've got here.
Matt Nielsen's listed as captain of
the Australian team and all of them.
There's nothing. Listen, maybe
they don't have one.
The OAC can't make them do that.
It's hard to favor one over another.
Yeah. Yeah.
You know, who knows? Maybe they're
contracted. Call for a hundred
thousand bonus if you're captain.
So they didn't get many.
Did the Americans get paid?
Big money could come any of the
links. So just don't winnings.
You know, money at all. That's one
of the problems that the NBA player
see when they're risking an
injury with those big contracts.
But when you know, you can't
really hate somebody to come to
the Olympics. You're representing
your country. You're not here to
make money.
Glad to hear you said it.
I know it's been the same with
side-dividandest and playing in
New York. He loves playing for
Australia. But funds had had nice
tons because of the insurance.
He's on club diet. He used to
lean down. It's always an
argument.
But the Olympics you play for
your nation. You don't play for
yourself. You don't play for
anything but your country.
So it even suggests that they pay
these players as a joke.
Glad to hear that.
The NBA player is on the
top of the game.
He's playing for the USI.
Playing ahead of the chance to
green the green gold Australia.
That's for sure. But still working
had it 90 seconds.
Durant.
Durant was cut off on the inside
and he took everyone by surprise
going that strong.
That's a good deal. The lob pass
down.
How about that?
Well, you know, the NBA
player in the NBA plays
made sure the photographers in
this plenty of them here
are going to look at him. He hung
off the rim for such a long
time. They can produce some
good stuff when giving the
opportunity. And that was
certainly a monster until we get
another look at that.
Barlow with the foul.
That was how quick. One of the
great young scores in the NBA
wasn't that back the other way
a young star.
This absolute star.
Thank you, Oles Dreyle.
Williams hasn't missed yet from the free-fair line.
It's made six in a row.
The first one is a defensive player for most of his career.
The last few years he's come on offensively.
Opportunity where it's so often about in the NBA.
The caliber of play that comes around on the roster is there for
Fallon Westbrook.
It seems like as we come to the end of these quarter there's a lot of whistles.
Once again that move by Kevin Durant.
So just when Australia got close the US holes lead out.
Joe Ingol says not so fast.
Good played from Bala.
The 30 seconds left nice move to the hole and Williams can't get it to fall.
Comes delivered over.
Not the screen.
And loves laps of the way Williams ahead.
Anthony draws the foul and gets the free throw.
You see the Americans almost look for the foul.
So why committed?
There was no doubt about that.
The only reason that Banc was able to get close was until he could put a hand on
and give away the bonus.
Why even go nearing it?
I don't know and you'll have to ask the man for the game.
I know it's not necessarily the dumb thing but it's the smart thing to just sit and watch that occur.
If he misses, which he would lose the ball like that in an obvious situation,
managed well that time.
You're certainly not going to stop the shot from that far behind
but Anthony did free throw shooter and he can't get it to fall.
15 for Mello.
84-70.
That's the quarter-folding point.
3-4-3.
And Hapton nods and said it.
The US is scored again.
28 points and every quarter is so far.
Seven seconds left in this way.
The US is scored.
And offensive foul will be called an Aaron Bane.
And staring daggers at the referee with that look.
Don't five seconds to go in a chance for the Americans to get one last basket.
Durant dribbles it off his foot.
Williams comes up with it.
And that'll do it.
And three-quarters in a row the United States puts up 28 points.
84-70.
As we go into the fourth and final quarter,
the United States hasn't been able to pull away completely.
Australia is still hanging in there.
They're nice numbers.
Those three-28s for the Americans.
28 points of peace in that third period.
But you have to remember Australia got away to a 11-nothing lead within a minute.
Or just a little bit more.
So once the Americans got it back on board,
they had played their opposition.
And here's the start to the Australians.
Ingalls to mill for three.
Wonderful shot.
Then soon after that,
steals the ball.
Then fades Ingalls for another three.
Really impressed by that.
We'll say back in it.
There are 70 quality plays on the American roster.
But Ingalls told the love pass.
He's hit six or seven shots.
19.7 rebounds for a set.
Here's a complete basketball play.
Yeah.
No, he certainly is.
Nice touch there for Anderson.
The Australians.
But for the most part,
in Kobe had that stretch where he got eight in a row didn't he with.
It's just, they've got so many plays.
It's sort of what they've got from the bench to shoot.
They take it in turns.
Don't they?
Who's turn?
And it was one of the watch.
And how quick is the ramp?
Look at that.
The scoring leaders.
Angles and mills with 19.
Anthony and Williams with 15 for the US.
The ramp was 14.
But again, they're hearing a lot of playing time with other players.
Yeah, that's it.
That's the beauty of the United States.
And it's just a foul situation for Australia.
Bans with four.
Wording him with four.
Nelson three.
Barlow three.
Delavid over three.
Newly three.
And we are underway.
Fourth and final quarter.
United States.
Against Australia.
The winner makes it to the semi final.
Kevin Durant dribbles it off his foot.
Put one down by the US.
Anthony.
He'll take it.
Strong rebound by Australia.
David Anderson and Wissel and a foul.
And no indication.
What occurred there except for Barlow getting his fourth foul.
The US has love in the game now.
Along with Anthony.
Two points guards.
Williams and Paul and Kevin Durant.
So no James, no Kobe Bryant, no center.
But they have to his ball.
Angles.
Mark the foul screen.
Next touch by David Anderson inside.
Big boys.
Six eleven.
Two hundred and twelve centimeters.
Not able to do too much at the low post up against the quality of opposition.
But continues to work at both ends of the floor.
Nice defense.
Love to grand down hard.
Gets back up.
Nice ball movement.
Grace passing and David Barlow hits the three.
Every quarter, Australia comes back into it for a minute.
And then the last three minutes, David Barlow places basketball back in Europe.
Love charging for the rebound.
It'll either go on love or it'll go on Newly.
And from the look on Newly's face, it's not on love.
Barlow hits the pedal on the back from his coach and his teammates.
He sits down and petty meals back in.
He has to sit down.
That's his fifth foul.
He's out of the game.
He's in playing he's in one corner.
They're shooter.
And Kevin Grant can't get it to fall.
Here comes Mill.
Engels for three.
Three pound by low.
One.
James back in the lineup for the US.
James gives Barlow a little shove.
The crowd didn't like it.
Williams for three.
Patty Mill's good crop holder dribble.
They need to get Engels for ball.
Engels will offensive rebound and foul.
And the foul on Engels.
And say he pushed off going for the rebound.
He got a timeout.
He's out at states now.
Back up by 15.
Our score was 731 left to play.
USA 90.
Australia 75.
Take a listen to Britt Brown in the huddle.
Keep that score same set.
Small.
So that's one.
One.
Two.
Don't be wishy washing on tape.
Just come.
Squeeze them and come.
Always very control is Britt Brown.
Live in the situation.
And it's a tough situation.
Extremely tough situation.
The scoreboard shows.
There's Ron James and the ball.
Just think back a moment ago where he got a bit physical with Matt Delivert over who is there at the bottom of that.
Trying to chase the ball down.
That's not the incident I'm talking about.
The big story of Victoria has been guiding the Brown James and having the Brown James look after him when the Australians are taking it down to the pool.
It must be really give a built to not just look at him and go wow every 15 seconds.
And he's too busy concentrating on how to score.
That's a good ball player.
I love it.
21 years old.
The US has a 19 year old who has not seen any action in this game.
Matt's Anthony Davis, the number one draft pick in the NBA out of the university of Kentucky.
He's a big talk.
I'm saying a little bit of himself right on the phone.
No one's saying too much.
But D can move too.
He doesn't belong.
Obviously he will be it by one.
There's Paul and Lowe, the 50 offensive rebound.
He makes a lot of money doing exactly that.
And the Minnesota timber world.
And they're going to have an interesting international team coming back.
They'll sign a couple Russians.
They already have Ricky Rubio.
Paul is like volleyball out there.
How many mills?
Why open for three?
42 points for how many?
A minute had he had it.
He was open.
All the Australians were on their way down in the air.
They knew he would make it.
And a rich in foul on David Anderson.
He's getting close to the fifth foul as well.
How many mills is my 22 now?
And he has a look at it.
Look at that in the background.
The team standing up.
The reason they're hands, they knew it was coming.
It was in Beijing.
Lived here for Joe Engels in London.
That had he put his hand up and said to the world to the NBA.
And particularly, hey.
I'm not the biggest guy out there.
But Gio can hustle, I can shoot.
I can run the point.
And so the world knows now.
Love another offensive rebound for the United States.
And doors up strong.
A lot of bloody contact down there.
Working hard on the ninth thursday.
Kevin Webb.
I don't know if we'll get to see this again.
There's love.
A lot of hands on him.
And he just won't be denied.
There's nine defensive rebound.
Nine offensive rebound.
Wow.
So love to the line.
Those romp team.
Fourth foul on Delavadova.
A lot of the Australian players were out of foul.
We're in the same few minutes really can pass in 10.
Those were all starting to say to who he means with jumping out of his skinny mate.
One of the early buckets and looked like he was really going to become that joint amongst joints.
And he's done not much more.
Coach Chesky likes a team where everybody can score apparently.
Cameron known for being one of the best defensive players on the NBA in the last shot.
And he's going to go on the bronze games.
He's got Kobe on the wing.
Kobe Bryant.
And Australia is going to call a timeout here with 547 left to go.
They don't want it to get out of hand.
United States closing in on the century mark 96 to 78.
And certainly put our big numbers in this tournament to date.
98 against France.
126 against Argentina 99 against Loni.
He needed every one of those winning that game.
But just five points.
Nigeria 156 to 73.
That was ridiculous.
Well, that was the game where the team shot like 75% and he has to go at 35.7 minutes.
And is he 110 against them?
589 points in five games going into the quarterfinal.
And 96 on the board with still the best out of six minutes to come.
But Australia, playing as tough as they can.
They're not giving them anything.
They're in the corner to Williams.
There's just so much offensive firepower.
And Mills waves it to Kobe Bryant.
This is the first game where Bryant finally started to get on track a little bit.
And now you're very happy about that.
And so.
Engloss picks it back out.
Mills wanted it.
But Nielsen will take it.
And while for Matt Nielsen.
Five points for the Australian captain.
Mills playing very aggressive defense on Chris Paul.
James with 10 on the shot clock.
Kobe Bryant, they get out of his way when he gets in that kind of mood.
They just let him shoot.
And show what the heck was about.
The expression of space is used to seeing the Americans.
James, maybe some hardy tricks coming up.
Bryant's got a hard hand.
In the zone.
He is in the zone.
Bryant again.
Fast break.
Picks it from outside.
And the reaction from his team man.
And look out.
It's 25 points to margin.
Kobe has 20.
himself.
James behind the back to love.
And the lead was 12.
It's now 27.
You got to love what the Americans are doing.
We'll figure out the end to add to suggested it might be party time.
The tricks are coming.
It's a magic.
He was fairly respond with the three.
Look out.
The back again.
Paul is slowing down.
They're trying to get it to Kobe.
He'll shoot it from anywhere.
The Lovid Hilt would tie it up on a foul on Bryant.
Kobe Bryant's got to get tired after a while.
That arm's got to get a little tired.
I think so.
Look at that game.
A triple double.
Triple double.
11 points.
14 revows.
11 assists.
10 assists.
That one.
I'll throw you a little bit.
If you're just walking in the room, the United States is blowing this one open here in the fourth quarter.
Kobe Bryant was on fire.
107-80.
And another steal.
Allie Hilt has to down James Harden's from Chris Paul.
Showtime.
And that's why this was the hardest ticket to get.
Another steal.
And Paul tried to know what pass Paddy Mills comes right back.
Mills took two and he's found from behind.
Paddy Mills averaging 22 coming in.
He's got 22.
He's the go-to guard.
And see Paul took it away.
And then just lays it up there.
Harden hasn't made many minutes.
But he's taking advantage of what he gets.
The US taking some of the stars out of the line up here.
And now you'll see 19 year old Anthony Davis in the lineup for the United States for the first time.
He wears number 14.
And he will be a barring injury.
He will be a star for many years.
Mills 23.
He's got a lot of time to play.
And he's got a lot of time to play.
So the San Antonio Spurs hope to get a little bit more playing time.
But he has some superstar in front of him.
This is going to help the police as well.
He has to help the police.
The coach, the teammates.
And that's more importantly on the teams.
As soon as he did four years ago, the Olympics he's doing it again on the big stage.
And then he's going to have to do something else.
There's his confidence.
He can make that kind of shot.
Opportunity what it's often about in the NBA.
Australia had their opportunities early in this game.
They stuck in.
They fought hard.
28.
21 at quarter time.
Three.
Pass.
You know, foul on Davis.
The night of the USA and you know what's glory.
For 90 seconds, about 90 seconds ago, this was part of it.
Damn, Taddon.
Making it look hard at all.
That's what the USA can do.
And they'll move through to the semi-finals.
On their way to goal.
Maybe.
I'm going to go to the two minute mark.
This is a total.
I'm Bruce Presslow, Mark Dorn alongside.
I hope you've enjoyed this game.
The United States now will advance into the semi-finals.
He's a warning, don't leave because the last two in a bit minutes will not be fun.
I'd go with dollar.
I'm Craig with dollar.
Another steal and Harden will get another showtime.
It's limited minutes, but the minutes he gets is a license to do whatever you want.
I just like watching the bearded motion.
Mills.
That's the youngster of the Rebun.
Harden.
He's a good outside shooter.
Seven points at about two minutes.
One 17 to 84 are scored.
Believe it or not, it was close when we started the quarter.
It will make the highlight real too.
11, nothing in the opening minutes of the second half from Australia.
Since then, they've been absolutely dominated.
And Bains fouled out.
So the year's S will in Brown.
It's kind of hard to say.
I'm going to take ten left to play on this one.
Allie up.
Pass a little bit too strong.
The semi-finals will be set.
I'm going to take it through those.
Who plays who?
One 17, 84, 41 seconds left.
But Mellow Anthony takes it himself.
Really?
28 seconds left to play.
The United States.
Once again, coming out on top.
I'm going to take a game of it, but in the end, that was it.
So to do that after this, just see the Americans home.
Three seconds on the shot clock and I'm coming.
And a great rejection from Aaron Bain.
The game pocket all expired.
There's coach Jeff Skiesh, who managed to hit his counterpart, Brett Brown.
The fans got a little bit of showtime.
That's what they wanted to see.
Patty Mills, what a great game for Australia.
He and Joe Engels kept him in it for a while.
But in the end, the United States had a little bit too much firepower.
So it'll be Brian, 20 points.
All of them in the second half of the United States ran out and won it.
It's 19 to 86.
So Mark Durand, why don't you feature the matchups now going into the semi-finals?
Yep, there's that final score here.
So with the 33th point, we overestrella it.
The United States safely through to the semis where they will meet Argentina.
They defeated Brazil 82-77 in their quarterfinal.
The five point game and the first of the semifinals will be Russia against Spain.
Russia is competing with the one here, 83-74.
Spain over France 66-59.
Going through Australia again, Patty Mills, 26 points, Engels 19 points.
Newly had 10 and for the United States, all in the second half could be Brian's 20.
Ron Williams 18 to rant 14 to Ron James.
He had the 11 points, 14 rebounds and 11 assists in this game.
Gryppled double, Carmelo Anthony 17 points.
And the United States just too much offense.
And they get the victory.
19 to 86.
So Mark Durand, I'm Bruce Brothers.
I hope you enjoyed this one.
We'll see you in the semi-finals.